<texts>
    <text>
        Thus, from the war of nautre, from famine and death, the most exalted object which is wa are capalbe of conceiving, namely, the production of the higher animals, directly follows.There is grandeur in this view of life, with its several powers, having been originally breathed into a few forms or into one; and that, whilst this planet has gone cycling on according to the fixed law of gravity, from so simple a beginning endless froms most beautiful and most wonderful have been, and are being, evolved.
    </text>
    <text title="Scrooge" >
        External heat and cold had little influence on Scrooge. No warmth could warm, no wintry weather chill him. No wind that blew was bitter than he, no falling snow was more intent upon its purpose, no pelting rain less open to entreaty. Foul weather didn't know where to have him. The heaviest rain, and snow, and hail, and sleet could boast of the advantage over him in only one respect. They often 'came down' handsomely, and Scrooge never did. Nobody ever stopped him in the street to say, with gladsome looks, 'My dear Scrooge, how are you? When will you come to see me?' No beggars implored him to bestow a trifle, no children asked him what it was o'clock, no man or woman ever once in all his life inquired the way to such and such a place, of Scrooge.
    </text>
    <text>
        It was the Dover road that lay, on a Friday night late in November, before the first of the persons with whom this history has business. The Dover road lay, as to him, beyond the Dover mail, as it lumbered up Shooter's Hill. He walked up hill in the mire by the side of the mail, as the rest of the passengers did; not because they had the least relish for walking exercices, under the circumstances, but because the hill, and the harness, and the mud, and the mail, were all so heavy, that the horses had three times already come to a stop, besides once drawing the coach across the road, with the mutinous intent of taking it back to Blackheath.
    </text>
    <text author="Sir Walter A Raleigh" title="I Wish I Loved the Human Race" >
    I wish I loved the Human Race. I wish I loved its silly face. I wish I liked the way it walks. I wish I liked the way it talks. And when I'm introduced to one, I wish I thought "What Jolly Fun!
    </text>
    <text author="St Patrick" title="Rune of St Patrick" >
        At Tara today in this fateful hour
        I place all heaven with its power,
        and the sun with its brightness,
        and the snow with its whiteness,
        and fire with all the strength it hath,
        and lightning with its rapid wrath,
        and the winds with their swiftness along their path,
        and the sea with its deepness,
        and the rocks with their steepness
        and the earth with its starkness:
        all these I place,
        by God's almighty help and grace,
        between myself and the powers of darkness.
    </text>
    <text author="Rudyard Kipling" title="If" >
        IF you can keep your head when all about you
        Are losing theirs and blaming it on you,
        If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you,
        But make allowance for their doubting too;
        If you can wait and not be tired by waiting,
        Or being lied about, don't deal in lies,
        Or being hated, don't give way to hating,
        And yet don't look too good, nor talk too wise:

        IF you can dream - and not make dreams your master;
        If you can think - and not make thoughts your aim;
        If you can meet with Triumph and Disaster
        And treat those two impostors just the same;
        If you can bear to hear the truth you've spoken
        Twisted by knaves to make a trap for fools,
        Or watch the things you gave your life to, broken,
        And stoop and build 'em up with worn-out tools:

        IF you can make one heap of all your winnings
        And risk it on one turn of pitch-and-toss,
        And lose, and start again at your beginnings
        And never breathe a word about your loss;
        If you can force your heart and nerve and sinew
        To serve your turn long after they are gone,
        And so hold on when there is nothing in you
        Except the Will which says to them: "Hold on!"

        IF you can talk with crowds and keep your virtue,
        Or walk with Kings - nor lose the common touch,
        If neither foes nor loving friends can hurt you,
        If all men count with you, but none too much;
        If you can fill the unforgiving minute
        With sixty seconds' worth of distance run,
        Yours is the Earth and everything that's in it,
        And - which is more - you'll be a Man, my son!
    </text>
    <text author="Wilfred Owen" title="Futility">
        Move him into the sun -
        Gently its touch awoke him once,
        At home, whispering of fields unsown.
        Always it woke him, even in France,
        Until this morning and this snow.
        If anything might rouse him now
        The kind old sun will know.

        Think how it wakes the seeds, -
        Woke, once, the clays of a cold star.
        Are limbs, so dear-achieved, are sides,
        Full-nerved,- still warm,- too hard to stir?
        Was it for this the clay grew tall?
        - O what made fatuous sunbeams toil
        To break earth's sleep at all?
    </text>
    <text author="Percy Bysshe Shelley" title="Ozymandias" >
        I MET A TRAVELLER from an antique land
        Who said: Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
        Stand in the desert. Near them on the sand,
        Half sunk, a shattered visage lies, whose frown
        And wrinkled lip and sneer of cold command
        Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
        Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
        The hand that mocked them and the heart that fed.
        And on the pedestal these words appear:
        "My name is Ozymandias, King of Kings:
        Look on my works, ye mighty, and despair!"
        Nothing beside remains. Round the decay
        Of that colossal wreck, boundless and bare,
        The lone and level sands stretch far away.
    </text>
    <text autohr="William Shakepspeare" title="To be, or not to be" >
        To be, or not to be, that is the question:
        Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer
        The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune,
        Or to take arms against a sea of troubles
        And by opposing end them?
        To die: to sleep;
        No more; and, by a sleep to say we end
        The heart-ache and the thousand natural shocks
        That flesh is heir to, 'tis a consummation
        Devoutly to be wish'd. To die, to sleep;
        To sleep: perchance to dream: ay, there's the rub;
        For in that sleep of death what dreams may come
        When we have shuffled off this mortal coil,
        Must give us pause.
    </text>

</texts>
